# 你看 小花狗
Look! A tinted puppy
# 它吃得好飽啊 你看 肚子上
She has eaten a lot! Look! Her belly,
# 吃得好[SIC]飽飽的
is stuffed with food.
# 它正在睡覺 我把它拉起來的
She was sleeping. But I pulled her out.
# 這條狗很像以前的那條公狗哦
This puppy looks really like our lost boy.
# 都沒有這樣的狗 生出來就這樣子的 哈哈
We don't have such a dog here. But she was born with this colour. Ha ha
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 這個是母的 這個
It's a girl, yea.
# 遺傳它爺爺的 遺傳
She has inherited the genes,
# 遺傳它爺爺的基因
she has inherited the genes from her grandpa.
# 過來
Come here!
# 通通給我過來
Everybody come here!
# 都不肯過來 小狗
They're not coming, the puppies.
# 握握手
Shake hand with me!
# 大胖子
Big fat girl
# 看看
Have a look!
# 容易掉毛
She sheds a lot.
# 不敢動是不是
You don't dare to move, do you?
# 沒事的 動一動啊
No worries! Just move
# 要有點表情 (註︰「表情」這個概念很難找到相對的翻譯。"Facial expressions"是指一般的面部表情，與這裡的不一樣)
Happy or not, show me!
# 笑一笑哇 你怎麼不笑呢
Have a smile. Why don't you smile?
# 笑一笑十年少 你知道嗎
A single smile makes you ten years younger, got it?
# 我天左餵了你 吃好喝好
I feed you everyday. You have good food and food drinks.
# 你還怕我幹嘛
So why are you still scared of me?
# 你看 它很喜 它這樣很喜黏著我的哦
Look! She likes, she really likes clinging onto me.
# 天天跟我 想 想 想跟我回家
Everyday she was, she was hope, hope, hoping to go home with me.
# 我不讓它回
But I don't let her come with me.
# 給它按一下摩 按一下脖子
Let me give her a massage, a massage on her neck.
# 看它很享愛的樣子
See how much she enjoys it?
# 看一下我
Look at me!
# 怎麼不看
Why don't you look at me?
# 看著我幹嘛
Why are you looking at me?
# 看著我就一直一動不動
She stares at me, like statue.